-你好  -鸡汤面条Campbell来了
-Hey, what's up? -Hey, it's Chicken-Noodle Campbell.
你不是应该坐在高脚椅子上吗
Shouldn't you be sittin' in a high chair?
法医的报告
Coroner's report.
你一直抽烟还不如直接吸毒呢
Why don't you just try crack?
你觉得自己这样很幽默吗
You call that humor?
长官说别再打976了
The Captain says no more 976 calls.
念珠先生 你得到其他地方寻找更高的启示
Mr. Love Beads, you'll have to seek higher enlightenment somewhere else.
我是中尉Cole 负责处理这件案子
I'm Lieutenant Cole. Been assigned to the case.
他们要求我来看看这份文件
They asked me to come and look at the file.
我并不想这样失礼 很高兴见到你
Didn't mean to be discourteous. Nice to meet you.
我听说过你 但没想到会这么快遇到你
I heard about you. I wasn't expecting you so soon.
-你在纽约工作 DeMarco谋杀案  -是的
-You worked in New York, right? DeMarco killings? -Yes,sir.
这里不是纽约 这也不是DeMarco谋杀案
This ain't New York and this ain't the DeMarco killings.
我们是讲究合作的
We work as a team around here.
我只想破这个案子
You know, the way I work is I just like to solve the case.
我甚至不在乎功劳归谁
I don't even care who gets the credit.
说得好 就这样
Beautiful. That's that.
我们叫这家伙"居家男人"
We call this guy, "The Family Man".
过去八个月他杀了六个家庭
He's killed six families in the last eight months.
都是仪式杀人
All ritual killings.
你发现受害人间有什么联系吗
Have you found any connection between the victims at all?
除了他们全部是天主教徒
Other than the fact that they're all Catholic which ties
以十字架的形式被钉死外 就没了
into the crucifixion ritual, no.
Jim 刚刚又发现两起
Hei, Jim! They just found two more.
最新的命案 今天是你的幸运日 我们走吧
Fresh kill. Today's your lucky day. Let's go.
这不一样 Jim
This ain't the same, Jim.
是的 这是第一次在汽车旅馆中发生
Yeah, this is the first one in a motel.
其余的都是在受害者家中
All the rest have taken place in their houses.
一般来说 我们能确认受害夫妇的身份 但是
Normally, we can lD the couple, but...
除此之外 作案手法非常相似
other than that, it's pretty much the same MO.
不 不仅仅如此 这次是完全不同的
No, there's a lot more than that goin' on. I mean, this is different.
问一下...你结婚了吗
So...Are you married or what?
这是我为什么讨厌新搭档的原因
This is what I hate about new partners.
他们总是想知道别人的情况
They always want to get personal.
-我并不想谈论这个 好吗  -好吧
-I don't want to talk about it, all right? -Okay.
-忘记我刚才说的  -很好
-Forget that I ever mentioned anything at all. -Good.
你结婚了吗
Are you married, or what?
没 没结婚
No, I'm not married.
我知道的每个已婚警官 都有一个不想和他睡觉的妻子
Every cop I know who's married, has a wife who won't sleep with him...
两个不听他话的小孩
two kids who don't listen to him...
和一条宁可舔自己也不愿去取报纸的狗
and a dog that'd rather lick himself than fetch the paper.
所有单位速到圣埃德蒙学校
All units respond to a barricaded suspect with hostages...
一持枪嫌犯挟持了人质
at the Saint Edmund's School.
-可能是自杀  -收到 我们马上到
-Possible suicide. -Yeah, we're in that area.
-你在干什么  -就在这附近啊
-Hey, what are you doin'? -It's right over here.
不 那是自杀 而我们是凶杀组
No, man. That's suicide. We're Homicide.
如果有傻瓜想要跳楼 那是他自己的问题
If some dumb ass wants to jump off a buildin', that's his problem.
如果有人把他推下楼的话 再来找我
Somebody pushes his ass off a buildin', then call me.
我的看法是 死亡都一样
The way I look at it, death is death.
我们必须对死者抱有同情心 还有快死的
We gotta have compassion for the dead, the dying...
可能快死的 快要死的
the could-be-dying and the about-to-be-dead.
我去 我去 行了吧
I'm going. I'm going.
快快快
Faster, come on. Quickly, quickly.
侦探Cole 侦探Campbell 什么情况
Detective Cole. Detective Campbell. What have we got?
一个叫Johnny Deverell的男孩 他是高年级的
A boy named Johnny Deverell. He's a senior.
他拿了一把枪 在一个全是小孩的教室里
He's got a gun and a class full of kids.
真是好啊
That's nice.
-他想要干什么  -我不知道
-What does he want? -I don't know.
他的女朋友和他分手了 他女朋友也在里面
His girlfriend broke up with him. He's got her up there too.
他以前还惹过什么别的麻烦吗
Has he been in trouble before?
他曾因毒品而被捕 他们让他看过医生
He was arrested for drugs. They had him seeing a therapist.
是啊 一定是没找对医生
Yeah, must have been the wrong therapist.
让每个人保持安静 把每个人都带离现场
Keep everybody quiet. Keep everybody back.
你知道这不关我们的事
Man, you know this ain't our gig.
这就是一个陷入苦恋的小孩
Look, it's a love-sick kid.
持枪的陷入苦恋的小孩 国家为什么培训特种部队
A well-armed, love-sick kid. Why do you think they got SWAT?
因为穿一身黑看起来很帅
'Cause they look good in black.
尽量给我找几部移动电话
See if you can get me a couple of cell phones right away.
Johnny 停下 他们会伤害你的
Johnny, please stop it. They're gonna hurt you.
闭嘴 Millie 我现在没心情想这个
Shut your mouth, Millie! I'm not in the mood for this!
放下枪 Johnny
Put the gun down, Johnny.
-放下  -闭嘴
-Just put it down! -Shut up!
Johnny 停下 求你了 Johnny **
Johnny, stop it! Please, Johnny!
我是洛杉矶警局的侦探Cole
This is Detective Cole, LAPD.
我不是来伤害你的 我是来帮助你的
I'm not here to hurt you. I'm here to help you.
我必须和你谈谈
I gotta get into a dialogue with you...
在那些穿黑衣服的家伙到这前 因为他们不听任何人的话
before the guys in black get here, 'cause they don't listen to anybody.
我不想你受到伤害
I don't want you to get hurt.
请你走到窗户这 然后看着我
I want you to step over to the window and look at me.
你会看见我是没带枪的
You'll see that I'm unarmed.
谁都别动
Nobody move!
过来 走到窗户这 看着我
Come on over. Step over to the window and look at me.
对不起 Johnny 放下枪
Sorry, Johnny. Put the gun down.
我不想开枪打你 你也不想死
I don't want to shoot you, and you don't want to be dead.
为什么不
Why not?
放下枪 别犹豫了
Drop the gun! Come on.
你怎么了
What are you on?
少跟我套近乎
Don't talk to me like you know me!
你想让我开枪吗
You want me to start shooting?
对 我不认识你
You're right, I don't know you.
我这就放下我的枪
I'm gonna put my gun down.
我们好好谈谈
We'll start out like this.
到底是有什么问题
Now, what's the problem?
你不了解
You don't understand, man.
你不了解 我不能和他回去
You don't understand. I can't go back with him.
我不能 我也不会
I can't, I won't.
和谁
With who?
你不了解 我不能和他回去
You don't understand. I can't go back with him.
和谁
With who?
我不能 我不会
I can't. I won't.
我爱你 Johnny
I love you, Johnny!
我也爱你
I love you, too.
我讨厌这工作
I hate this job.
-冷静  -等等
-Calm down, son. -Wait!
小心头 冷静
Watch your head. Calm down.
你看 特种部队肯定会杀了这个男孩
Now, you see? SWAT would have killed this boy.
你知道 我也知道
You know it, and I know it.
-你不是自由作家  -不是
-You're not a freelancer, okay? -Oh, no.
这不是纽约
This ain't New York.
当然不是
No shit.
Frank Deverell 怪不得
Frank Deverell. It figures.
富人的小孩都是混蛋
Rich people's kids are always fucked up.
中尉 哪里能找到侦探Cole
Lieutenant, where will I find Detective Cole?
-就在那边 先生  -谢谢你
-Right down there, sir. -Thank you.
-侦探Cole  -是的 先生
-Detective Cole? -Yes, sir.
我衷心感谢你
I'd like to thank you from the bottom of my heart...
阻止了我继子自杀
for not letting my stepson take his own life.
你看起来是个真诚的人 我
You look like a very sincere individual, and I...
真的感激你过来 您真是太好了
really appreciate your coming down. So nice of you.
那我真诚地希望 如果有需要我帮忙的
Well, I sincerely hope that if there's ever anything I can do for you...
请一定告诉我
you won't hesitate to ask me.
有需要的话我会第一个就拨你的号码
You'll be the first one I dial.
我们走吧
Let's get out of here.
外套不错
Nice coat.
侦探Cole 我能和你谈一下吗
Detective Cole, can I have a minute?
我现在很忙
I'm kind of busy right now.
就几句 Deverell先生让我
I'll be very brief. Mr. Deverell asked me to speak to you...
代表他继子跟你谈谈
on behalf of his stepson.
关于什么
About what?
Deverell先生感觉你的证言会非常有帮助
Mr. Deverell feels your testimony would be very helpful...
在争取Johnny因暂时精神不正常被判无罪时
in getting Johnny acquitted on grounds of temporary insanity.
有个小问题 首先 我不认为他精神不正常
There's a little problem. First of all, I don't think he's insane.
第二 我喜欢实话实话
Second of all, I like to testify as to what actually happened.
探员 是这样
Look, Detective...
Johnny在经历一段非常困难的时期
Johnny's been going through a very difficult time.
他需要治疗 而不是监禁
He needs treatment, not prison.
你可能也知道 Deverell先生
Now, Mr. Deverell, as you may know...
是个非常重要的人 非常有影响力
he's a very important man, and a man with a lot of influence...
他可以成就或摧毁一个人的事业
a man who could help or hurt a career.
你是为这个男人做什么的
Just what is it that you do for this man?
我是负责Deverell先生的安全的
I'm in charge of Mr. Deverell's security.
差点把我搞糊涂了 我以为你是一位律师 听着
Could have fooled me. I thought you were an attorney.Listen...
请帮我带个话
I want you to deliver a message for me.
告诉你的混蛋老板 没有人 没有人能威胁我
You tell your asshole boss that nobody, nobody threatens me.
了解了 我会把你的感受告诉Deverell先生
I understand. I'll convey your feelings to Mr. Deverell.
现在给我滚出去 别再出现在我面前
Now get your ugly, white ass out of here. And don't come back.
汽车旅馆受害人有一些问题
The motel victim had some problems...
你可能想要知道
l thought you might want to know about.
除了头部中枪 被钉十字架吗
Besides bein' shot in the head and crucified?
你要告诉我什么 她经历了不如意的一天吗
What are you gonna tell me, she had a bad-hair day?
她本来也就可能会在几个月内死亡
She would have been dead in a couple of months.
为什么
From what?
我发现了晚期骨肉瘤 和间质性纤维化
I found advanced osteosarcoma and interstitial fibrosis.
如果你不用英语说 我会用字典打死你
If you don't say it in English, I'll beat you to death with a dictionary.
是一种罕见的骨癌 而且扩散到全身了
It's a rare form of bone cancer, and this cancer had spread throughout her body.
-什么引起的  -我是什么 先知吗
-What'd cause that? -What am I? The Amazing Randy?
我们得测试 会花点时间
We have tests to run, it will take time.
指纹方面有什么发现吗
What'd you come up with on prints?
没有 我认为她不是本地人
Nothing. I don't think she's local.
我也这么认为 我甚至认为她不是美国人
Neither do I. I don't even think she's American.
我认为她是俄国人
I think she's Russian.
等等 我以为他才是先知呢
Wait, I thought he was the Amazing Randy.
头发 颊骨
Hair...cheekbones...
遗传骨骼结构 我认为她是俄国人 很有可能是格鲁吉亚人
genetic bone structure. I think she's Russian, most likely Georgian.
你就这么看她一眼就得出这些结论
You can tell all that just by lookin' at her?
是啊 她是水瓶座的 喜欢乡村音乐
Right. She's an Aquarius and likes country music.
曾经是水瓶座
Was...an Aquarian.
精神已经离开了身体
You see, the spirit has left the body.
摆在这儿的 只是一个破碎的容器
What we have here is a mere broken vessel.
"一个破碎的容器"
"A broken vessel?"
关于这具躯体 你还有什么想要评价的
Anything else interesting about the body that you'd like to comment on or...
她的胸很好看
She's got nice tits.
完全正确 但是有点太好看了
Precisely, Grasshopper, but a little bit too nice.
好了 伙计 查查这个序列号
Okay, partner, run this number.
侦探Cole不想合作
Detective Cole's not gonna cooperate.
这是新手常有的毛病啊
That's the problem with new cops.
应当教教他们应该听谁的
They need to be taught who to pay attention to.
我很高兴给他上这一课
I'd be happy to teach him that lesson.
让我们的俄国朋友对付他
Put some of our Russian friends on it.
这次变变 让他们自己努力挣钱吧
Let them earn their money for a change.
其它事情还正常吗
Everything else in shape?
一切正常
Like clockwork.
所有人都还毫无知情吗
Everyone's still in the dark?
紧锁消息 只要每个人都闭上他们的嘴
It's a very tight seal, as long as everyone keeps their mouth shut.
他们会的
They will.
我们已经给他们树了一个好榜样
I think we've set a very good example.
为什么来洛杉矶 纽约的神经病对你来说不够多吗
So, why LA? New York didn't have enough psychopaths for you?
我和我的上司相处得不好
I didn't get along with my captain.
是改变的时候了 前妻把孩子们都带来这了
Figured it was time for a change. The ex moved out here with the kids.
你们继续聊...
Yeah. Y'all just go on....
不 谢谢你 我不太认识你
No, thank you, I don't know you that well.
不 那是茶 好东西
No, that's tea. That's good stuff.
鹿角做的 可提升你的阳刚之气
It's deer antler. It's good for your masculinity.
我没什么问题 多谢你的好意
Ain't nothin' wrong with my manhood, thank you.
让我喝一小口
Let me just have a little sip.
这是我最喜爱的电影
This is my favorite movie.
你知道我是黑人吗 我完全不知道你在说什么
Do you know I'm black? I have no idea what you're saying.
她说那部电影使她哭
She says that movie always makes her cry.
是 那是一部赚人眼泪的电影
Yeah, that's a real tearjerker.
不是说我会看电影哭或什么的
Not that I cry at movies or anything like that.
仅仅一个忧伤的场景可赚不到我的眼泪
It takes more than a sad scene to break me, you know what I mean?
你应该偶尔哭一下 能使灵魂清洁
Once in a while you should cry 'cause it cleanses the soul.
你会需要的
You could use a little bit of that.
如果我需要清洁 我有糠麸饼 多谢
If I need cleansing, I have a bran muffin. Thank you.
这里没有纸巾*
You ain't gonna find one here.
该死
Shit.
我可能对这香味过敏
I think I'm allergic to the incense.
你们卖蟑螂 天哪 我选错行了
Y'all sell roaches? Damn, I'm in the wrong business.
我要是干这个 不用离开我的公寓就能赚钱
I could make money and never leave my apartment.
把这个放到你舌头下面
Just put this underneath your tongue.
对过敏很有效 立刻就会让你恢复
It's perfect for allergies. It'll clear you right up.
有些苦
This is bitter.
苦吗 我不知道为什么它是苦的
Bitter? I don't know why it'd be bitter.
这是什么
What is this?
只是一点鹿鞭粉
It's just a little bit of powdered deer penis.
真搞笑啊 你真幽默啊 太侮辱人了
That's real funny. That's real fuckin' funny. Damn, do I feel violated.
告诉我 你这珠子到底怎么回事
So tell me, what's up with the beads?
这些吗 这叫玛拉 藏族祈祷用的珠子
These here? It's called a mahla. Tibetan prayer beads.
你用这些来干吗
What do you use 'em for?
我用它们使自己冷静 净化我的思想
I use them to calm my mind and to purify my thoughts.
我用威士忌
Yeah, I use Jack Daniel's.
我们有同样的目的
We're tryin' to go to the same place.
只是方法不同而已
We're just using a different technique.
只是我不用把酒瓶子戴在脖子上
Except I don't wear the bottle around my neck.
因为如果你那么做的话 会失去工作
That's because you'd lose your job if you did.
呼叫4K63 刚刚收到线人的电话
Roden to 4 King 63. Just got a call from an informant...
说有"居家男人"的消息
who claims to have info on The Family Man.
他说只把消息给你们 在南部码头等你们
Says he'll only give it to you. Waitin' on the south dock.
4K63收到 我们马上去码头
This is 4 King 63. We're on our way.
你看 他们闯进了那部车
See? They're breakin' into a car over there.
我们是来这里见线人的 没时间搭理他们
We're here to meet an informant. We don't have time for that.
我们是警察 就应该立刻抓坏蛋
We're police. We gotta get the bad guys once in a while.
干脆给你一双红靴子和斗篷...
Why don't we get you some red boots and a cape...
这样你就能绕着城市飞 阻止所有的犯罪
and you can fly around the city and stop all the crime?
警察 别动
Police! Freeze!
知道什么让我恼火吗 就是看到像你们一样的混蛋
You know what pisses me off? When I see some sorry-ass motherfuckers...
头发比我多
like you with more hair than me.
转过身 把手放到车上...
Turn around, put your goddamn hands on the car...
别逼我发飙
before I go get my clippers and go crazy in here.
去死 猪头
Fuck you, pig.
"去死" 他说"去死"吗
"Fuck you?" Did he say, "Fuck you"?
我很迷惑 我们有徽章 我们有枪
I'm confused. We got the badges. We got the guns.
你们只有一把螺丝刀
You got a screwdriver.
你们拿一把螺丝刀参加枪战吗
It's kind of like takin' a screwdriver to a gunfight.
猪头 这可是旧词儿
And "pig," that's an old phrase.
你们一定不是这里的人 你们一定是别的国家的
Y'all must not be from around here. Y'all must be from another country...
放下枪 拜托
Drop the guns. Please.
这是警察办事 不关你们的事
This is a police matter. It's got nothin' to do with you.
放下枪
Drop the guns.
我们只能来硬的了
Think we're gonna have to do this the hard way.
我不能打架
I can't fight, man.
"不能打架" 什么意思 这个时候正是告诉我的好时机啊
What do you mean you can't fight? It's a fine time to tell me now.
跪下 马上
Get down on your knees. Now.
他喜欢你 这是个好消息
He likes you, that's the good news.
对不起 没有晚饭和电影我不会跪的
Sorry. Not without dinner and a movie.
你朋友喜欢来硬的 你呢
Your friend likes to do things the hard way. Now, how about you?
我的朋友 他喜欢乡村音乐 而我喜欢摇滚
My friend, he's a little bit country, I'm a little bit rock-n'-roll.
什么意思
What does that mean?
只是个表达 你要什么
Just an expression. What do you want?
要你死
You...dead.
为什么
Why?
因为价钱很好
Because the pay is so good.
那我加倍如何
Well...How about if I double the pay?
你有胆儿 不过我不认为你有足够的钱
You have balls. But I don't think you have enough money.
我有的
Well, I do.
我兜里有几千块
I got thousands of dollars in my pocket.
我这就把手伸进后面的口袋 拿出我的钱包
I'm gonna reach into my back pocket slowly to get my wallet.
我有很多现金...
I have a lot of cash...
-或者你们可以拿走塑料卡  -塑料
-or you could take plastic. -"Plastic?"
这就是摇滚
This is rock-n'-roll.
你不是说你不能打架嘛
For a minute I forgot you said you can't fight.
我不是不能打
It's not that I can't fight.
-是不应该出手 有违我的信仰  -好的
-I'm not supposed to. It's against my religion. -Great.
我是佛教徒
I'm a Buddhist.
你是功夫牧师
You're a Kung Fu priest.
谁派你来的
Who sent you, man?
俄罗斯黑手党
The Russian Mafia.
-让我试试  -你会说俄语
-Let me try. -You speak Russian?
一点点
A little bit.
快说 不然我扁死你 混蛋
Answer me, goddamn it, before I beat the shit out of you, you dumb ass!
-你俄语讲得很好  -是的 俄语黑话
-You speak good Russian. -Yes. Black Russian.
把他的权利说一下 虽然他不省人事
Read him his rights even though he's a little unconscious.
他知道的
He knows 'em.
我告诉你 长官 这家伙非常怪
I'm tellin' you, Captain, this guy is weird.
嗯 哪个警察不怪
Yeah, show me a cop who isn't.
我并不是说他着装奇怪
Look, I'm not talkin' about a cop who wears pantyhose.
他讲中文 穿得像个和尚...
This guy, he speaks Chinese, he dresses like a monk...
昨天的俄国佬 他像李小龙那样扁他们 比李小龙还酷
and the Russians yesterday, he took those guys out like Bruce Lee, only better.
我看见他把信用卡当作忍者刀来用
I mean, I saw him use his credit card like a goddamn Ginsu knife.
那会是从哪学的
Where would you learn that?
不知道 也许是在军队中学的
I don't know, maybe the Army.
你想我怎么做 Jim 看他的履历吗
What do you want me to do, Jim, look at his resume?
别拿这些东西烦我 和他一起干活就是了
Don't come to me with this kind of shit. Just work with the guy.
和他一起干活
"Work with the guy".
你觉得这是什么意思
What does this say to you?
惩罚和净化
Punishment and purification.
他认为他是在帮这些人 把他们变成殉道士
He believes he's helping these people by turnin' them into martyrs.
但是他不满足
Only he can't get any satisfaction.
他不断做这些 越来越大胆...
So he keeps doin' it, gettin' bolder and bolder...
直到他被抓或被杀
until he's either caught or killed.
他也不是从魔鬼那接受命令
And he ain't gettin' his orders from the Devil, either.
他相信他听到的是耶稣的声音
He believes he's listenin' to Jesus himself.
你学得很好 兄弟
You learn well, Grasshopper.
专案组 我是Campbell
Task force, Campbell.
好的
All right.
又多了两具尸体
Two more bodies.
嘿 慢一点
Hey, slow down.
没事的 我们一会儿回来
It's all right, man, we'll be back later.
把这新手带离犯罪现场
Hey, man, get this virgin off the crime scene.
Andrew Dunleavy 精神病医生
We got Andrew Dunleavy, a psychiatrist.
他妻子Ellen 还有两个小孩...
This is his wife Ellen. There are two children...
不过我们还没找到他们
but we haven't been able to locate them.
别说了 别说了
Roden, squash that, man.
你还好吗 Jack
Are you all right, Jack?
-Jim 有空吗  -当然
-Jim, you got a minute? -Sure.
小心 他想借钱 我一看他的面部神情就知道
Careful, he wants to borrow money. I know that look.
-给你看些东西  -什么
-Got somethin' for you to look at. -What is it?
在Dunleavy案件犯罪现场受害女子的身上找到一个指纹
Found a print at the Dunleavy scene, on the woman's body.
太好了 正是时候
Beautiful. It's about time.
-立刻分析  -已经分析过了
-Let's run it right away. -Already did.
是Cole的
It's Cole's.
-你的兄弟还在联邦调查局工作  -是
-Your brother still works for Intelligence, right? -Yeah.
-让他找到一切关于Cole的资料  -好
-Tell him to find out everything he can on Cole. -All right.
非正式的
Off the record.
挨家挨户的搜索扩大四个街区
We'll extend the house-to-house canvas by four blocks.
寻找被害者之间的联系 他们购物的场所...
We're lookin' for any links between the victims. Where they shop...
...修车的地方 冲洗照片的地方
get their cars repaired, pictures developed...
...无论多细微的东西
anything, no matter how small.
帮个忙 给我一些这些犯罪现场的照片中
Do me a favor and get me copies of these blood paintings on the walls...
墙上的血画的复印件
in this stack of crime-scene photos.
把它们发到所有的精神病病房和监狱
Send 'em out to every psych ward and prison throughout the US.
也许犯人是受害者治疗过的病人
Maybe a former patient.
我不知道 我只是觉得...
I don't know, I just think that...
这作品这么奇特 任何犯人 精神病医生或牧师
this work is so unique that any prisoner, psychiatrist or priest...
都不会忘记它
would definitely not forget it.
好的 所有人都知道该干什么
All right, everybody knows what to do.
各自行动吧
Let's go.
不 我能理解
No, I understand.
我会尽快到那里
I'll get there as fast as I can.
多谢
Thanks.
嘿 你回来早了
Hey, you're home early.
怎么了
What's up?
我有个新病人 他们认为她快不行了 所以...
I have a new patient. They don't think she has a long time to live, so....
怎么了
What's wrong?
又发生了一起凶杀案
There's been another killing.
同一个家伙吗
Same guy?
是的
Yeah.
我很抱歉 Jack
I'm sorry, Jack.
他杀了Ellen和她的丈夫
He killed Ellen and her husband.
什么
He did what?
我得告诉我的孩子们 他们的母亲死了
I gotta go tell my kids that their mother is dead.
天哪 Jack
Jesus, Jack!
他开始针对我了
I think he's makin' it personal, you know?
西湖安保
Westlake Security.
请你告诉Smith先生 Jones先生想联系他...
I'd like you to tell Mr. Smith that Mr. Jones needs to contact him...
就现在
right away.
我想可能出了点事
I think there may be a problem.
说吧 孩子
Spit it out, son.
Jones先生要见你
Mr. Jones, he's asking to see you.
是吗
Really?
为什么过了这么久 他才来找我
I wonder what took him so long?
你想让我怎么做
What would you like me to do?
别管他
lgnore him.
有人在对付他
He's being dealt with.
而我们有更大的鱼要钓
And we have bigger fish to fry.
听你的
Whatever you say.
"十个度过周末的方法"****
"Ten Ways To Spend Your Weekend".
这是我们找到的所有关于Cole的资料
This is all we could get on Cole.
让我们看看
Let's see.
纽约警察局 特遣部队 调查DeMarco系列凶杀案
NYPD, Homicide, Task Force Command on the DeMarco serial killings.
很多奖章 好警察
Lots of medals, good cop.
他追到了那个DeMarco凶手
He tracked down the DeMarco killer...
在屋顶射杀了他
shot him on a rooftop, one-on-one...
因为没经允许而行动被降级
and then was busted for actin' without sanction.
两杯咖啡 Raffi  加糖
Two coffees, Raffi. Extra sugar.
我不要  两杯都是我的
-No coffee for me. -They're both for me.
有什么其他的事情吗
Anything else?
军队记录里什么都没有
Nothin' in the military records.
当纽约警察前也没什么记录  就像这家伙凭空跳出来一样
Almost nothin' before the NYPD. Looks like this guy came out of nowhere.
你意思是我们对这家伙 一无所知吗
Are you tellin' me we don't know nothin' about this guy?
是的 我们只知道一件事
Yeah, there's one thing we know for sure.
他和Dunleavy女人结过婚
He used to be married to the Dunleavy woman.
混蛋
Son of a bitch.
"在主的屋子里 有许多房间 如果不是这样...
"In my Father's house, there are many rooms. If it were not so...
"我会告诉你 我为你准备了一个地方吗
"...would I have told you that I go to prepare a place for you?
"Thomas 对他说 上帝 我们不知道你去哪
"Thomas said to him, 'Lord, we do not know where you are going.'
耶稣对他说 我是道路
"Jesus said to him, 'I am the way...'
真理和生命  没人见到上帝 除了我
"...and the truth and the life, no one comes to the Father, but by me".
你为什么不告诉别人 这是你前妻呢
Why didn't you tell anybody it was your ex-wife?
你知道他们会不让我 负责这案子的
You know they would have pulled me off the case.
你应该告诉我 我们是搭档
You should've told me. We're workin' together.
我没有
Well, I didn't.
我们知道了汽车旅馆夫妇的身份 Eugene和Sonya Roslv
We lD'd the couple at the motel. Eugene and Sonya Roslov.
俄国人 像你说的那样
Russian, just like you said.
和别人有什么联系吗
Any connection to the others?
没有 他们甚至不是天主教徒
No. They weren't even Catholic.
另外还有什么
There goes that theory. What's next?
这是空的
This is empty.
只是所有我们知道的关于你的东西
It's everything we know about you.
你毫无背景 除了烟雾和镜子
Your background's nothin' but smoke and mirrors.
你是谁 杰克
Who are you, Jack?
我现在没时间解释
I can't get into it right now.
也许你能解释
Yeah, well maybe you can get into this.
我们在你前妻的房子里 找到了你的指纹
We found your print at your ex-wife's house.
她是我前妻  我一直去她那接我孩子
She was my ex-wife. I pick up my kids there all the time.
指纹是在尸体上的
The print's on the body.
移植上去的
Planted.
还有一阵烟雾 从那绿色小山飘过来
And there's a puff of smoke comin' from the grassy knoll.
你到底 想干什么
What kind of bullshit you tryin' to run, man?
我不是一直当警察 这是我现在能告诉你的
I ain't always been a cop. That's all I can tell you right now.
你是个神秘人物
You are one mysterious motherfucker.
没人知道你的过去...
Nobody seems to know anything about your past...
...唯一的证据就和你有关
and the only evidence I got points right at you.
现在这让你担心了吗 杰克
Now, does that worry you, Jack?
我看起来担心吗
Do I look worried?
好的 这使我担心
Well, it damn sure worries me.
你好 Lento
Hello, Lento's.
不 对不起 我们关门了
No, I'm sorry, we're closed.
-不 这是私人午餐  -抱歉
-No. It's a private lunch. -Excuse me.
我帮不了你什么
There is nothing I can do.
我在告诉你我们关门了 明天我们才开
I'm telling you we're closed today. Tomorrow we'll be open.
很好 那时再来
It'll be fine. Come then. It'll be a nice...
抱歉 打扰一下
Excuse me a minute.
混蛋 你瞎了吗 我们关门了
Asshole, what are you blind? We're closed!
你说太多了
You kind of talk too much!
好的 来这 我们给你张桌子
Yeah, go ahead, come on over, we'll give you a table.
你太不可思议了 你在这干吗
You're unbelievable. What are you doing here?
你得转身 然后离开  这是你得做的
You need to turn around and leave. That's what you need to do.
你不打我电话 你不写信 更坏的是 你不接我电话
You don't call, you don't write. What's worse, you don't take my calls.
对不起 对不起 先生...议员...
Excuse me. Excuse me, sir...Senator....
为何我们
Why don't you and I take your little sensitive ponytail...
不离开这里呢
and your little sissy beads, and get out of here, okay?
如我所说...
As I was saying....
议员 如你所见 一些急事
Senator, as you can see, some urgent business has just come up.
多谢 议员
Thank you, Senator, so kind.
时间真长 杰克 T 你现在用这名字 对吗
It's been such a long time, Jack. That's the name you're using now, correct?
暂时
At the moment.
我能给你些东西尝尝吗  这些太美味了...
Can I get you a bite to eat? The food is truly wonderful...
虽然服务员有些东西 没说
although the service leaves a little to be desired.
别说废话 我要的是名字 咨询者的名字
Cut the shit. I need some names, names of consultants.
别告诉我 你照顾不了你自己
Don't tell me there's a problem you can't take care of yourself?
关于这系列凶杀 我想你知道
It's about the serial killings. I know you know about them.
是的 关于Ellen很抱歉
Yes, I do. Truly wicked. Sorry about Ellen.
很好的女人
Wonderful woman.
最后两个凶杀 绝对是专业杀手的杰作
You know, the last two murders were definitely the work of a pro...
... 不是连环杀手
not a serial killer.
我有这感觉 你知道这个专业杀手是谁
And I just have the feeling that you might know who this pro is.
好的 让我猜猜
Well, let me guess.
我们已经发现你多变的过去...
They've discovered your checkered past...
...而现在他们怀疑你
and now they suspect you.
并不准确
Not exactly.
他们还没完全了解我的过去  而我知道你了解
They're still not totally up on my past yet, but I know you are.
因此 我肯定你意识到 我能对你做什么...
Therefore, I'm sure you realize what I'm capable of doing to you...
...如果我不得不
if I have to.
是的 需要的话 我会做的
Yes, indeed, I do.
你找哪种咨询者
What kind of consultant you lookin' for?
那个个人主义者 给了我压力
This individual gives me the impression that he's a freelancer.
把连环杀手隐藏了起来
Hiding his targets in the scenario of a serial killer.
像a22*一样 就像暴头
Likes a .22, likes head shots.
看起来在死者死后 对他们的衣服有些破坏
Seems to be inflicting costume wounds on the victims after they're dead...
非常高超的清洗技巧
and has excellent cleaning skills.
我会去打听的
I'll certainly keep my eyes peeled, and my ears open.
现在那样还不够
Right now, that's just not gonna be good enough.
杰克 有个问题是 我现在很忙...
Jack, you know there's a problem. I'm kind of busy right now...
在国会作证
testifying before Congress.
他们对我们从哪取得基金 非常不满...
They're getting kind of cranky about where we get our core-op funds...
不过 为了你...
but, as it's you...
...我会尽我所能
I'll certainly do the best I can.
为了我们以前
For old times' sake.
很高兴见到你 哥们
Good to see you, buddy.
再见
Bye, buddy.
如果你再那样对我 我就杀了你
If you ever pull that shit with me again, I'll kill you.
你的所有中国药物 不会再救你一次
All your little Chinese, moo-shoo pork potions will not save you next time.
你不应该打烂中国药物
You shouldn't knock Chinese potions.
我口袋里有些东西...
I have something in my pocket right now...
能完全把你额头的淤青消掉
that'll completely clear up that bruise on your forehead.
什么淤青
What bruise?
那个
That bruise.
你合法停车了吗
Do you validate parking?
你好 Lento
Hello, Lento's.
不 不 不行的 我们要关门维修了 要...
No, no, no, that' won't work. We're closed for renovation. I'd say...
两个月 是的 谢谢
two months. Yeah. Thanks.
你和他一起追踪你的猎物
You're chasing your tail with this one.
他可能从跳蚤市场买来的 我们没办法在哪找到他
He probably bought it at a flea market. No way we're gonna find him there.
我们不得不重新开始 你们得好好研究
We're gonna have to go back to basics. You guys gotta do your canvassing.
-你的电话响了  -你没听我说话
-Your phone is ringing. -You're not listening to me.
看我的口...和那些人说话
Read my lips...talk to the people!
侦探 我叫Melanie Sardes
Detective, my name is Melanie Sardes.
我想我知道你找什么
I think I know who you're looking for.
我很抱歉我没早找你们 侦探 不过我没有每天
I'm sorry I didn't call you guys sooner, Detective, but I don't open...
开邮箱
my mail every day. There's so much, it kind of gets away from me.
我通常每星期在 监狱教两天艺术
I used to teach art two days a week up at the prison.
你发烧了
Do you have a cold?
不 我对香味过敏
No, I'm allergic to the incense.
我能给你什么吗
Can I get you something?
不用了 我要吸些鹿阳粉 我没事
No, thanks. I'm gonna go suck on some deer penis. I'll be all right.
就是中国鹿阳粉
It's a Chinese deer penis.
你把它放在...
You put it under your....
你说什么
You were saying?
我对你寄来的画很熟悉
Well, I knew the drawings you sent were familiar.
特别是光环
Especially the halos.
在我看到巨大的十字架时...
Then when I saw the titian crucifixion...
我突然想起来了
it just clicked.
他是我最喜欢的学生
He was my favorite student.
看到了吗 我所有的教学方法是有组织的
See, my whole approach is organic.
我从内在影响开始...
I start on the inside influence...
然后我试着去 设计学生的内在生活
and then I try to draw on the student's inner life.
正是让他们找到时候
It's about having them find the moment. A moment without...
我得赶快回到九十年代
I've got to hurry back to the nineties now.
你能不能只告诉我他的名字
Could you just give me his name?
Christopher Maynard
Christopher Maynard.
我们干得不错  我知道
-We're moving fast on this. -I know.
我们的逮捕证在哪
Where's our warrant?
等等 给我点时间
Wait, give me a minute.
怎么了
What's goin' on?
-你没听说  -是的 我没听说
-You didn't hear? -No, I didn't.
我们已经找到杀手了 名字和地址
We got a make on the killer. Name and address.
我们仅仅需要逮捕证
We're just waitin' for the warrants.
多谢你告诉我这些
Thank you so much for tellin' me.
我猜是Campbell告诉你的
Well, I figured Campbell told you.
是的 给我研究结果
Yes, get me Research.
你能帮我个忙 去查查是否...
Would you do me a favor and check if there's...
在929 Barrow街九个区内 有天主教堂
a Catholic Church within a nine-block radius of 929 Barrow Street?
祝福我 教父 我犯罪了
Bless me, Father, for I have sinned.
我有种感觉我今天会死
I had this feeling I was gonna die today!
Christopher
Christopher.
这样行不通 哥们 在教堂里...
This isn't gonna work, buddy. Here in a church...
会伤着牧师的
with the priest?
我不想伤害人
I don't want to be hurting people.
我不想
I don't like to.
我能和牧师说句话吗
Could I please speak with the priest?
你允许我 和教父说句话吗
Could I have your permission to please speak with the Father a minute?
我知道你不想伤害他
I know you don't want to hurt him.
教父...
Father...
来这里
come here, please.
现在
Right away.
离开这里
Get out of here.
他们在找我吗
Are they searching for me?
是的 长官
Yes, sir, they are.
你怎么知道我在这里
How did you know I'd be here?
我只是猜的  这是离你家最近的教堂
Well, I just took a lucky guess. It's the closest church to your home.
你是新来的警察
You're the new cop they brought in, right?
是的 长官 你怎么知道
Yes, sir, I am. How'd you know?
我留意这些事  这是我工作的一部分
I keep track of these things. It's part of my job.
这样 你知道
So, you know...
你杀了我前妻
you killed my ex-wife, don't you?
我想你知道我没伤害她
I want you to know I didn't hurt her.
你没有
You didn't?
我只杀了别人叫我一定要杀的
I only kill who I was told to kill, who I had to kill.
解决掉的
The Roslovs?
The Dunleavys
The Dunleavys?
你杀了他们吗
Did you kill them?
我放了他们
I was spared them.
另外人干的
Someone else was called.
谁叫你干的 Christopher
Who was given the call, Christopher?
这里太痛苦了 我得走了
There's too much pain here. I gotta go now.
听我说
Listen to me.
你停下
You, stay!
听我说
Listen to me.
祝福我 教父 我已犯罪了  我最后的招认...
Bless me, Father, for I have sinned. My last confession...
-是六个月前  -Christopher
-was six months ago. -Christopher, please....
那你帮我
Then you help me.
-你帮我  -我不能这么做
-You help me. -I can't do that.
我在地狱 我在地狱
I am in hell! I am in hell!
听我说 听我说
Listen to me. Listen to me.
你不这么做我就杀了你
Do it now or I will kill you! You believe it?
-一...二...  -这是上帝的房间
-One...two.... -This is God's house.
-别逼我
-Don't make me do this. -Please.
-别  -三
-Don't! -Three!
这是Maynard的枪 帮我留着
This is Maynard's gun. Book it for me.
这太坏了 杰克
This is bad, Jack. This is real bad, man.
我不能为了输而赢
I can't win for losin', man.
我不想让这事发生
I tried so hard not to let this happen.
我们搜索了他的房子 找到了 所有的工具
We tossed his house, we found all kinds of shit: barbed wire, spikes....
-他正是我们找的那家伙  -
-He was definitely our guy. -Shit.
你在这干什么
What the fuck are you doin' here?
我只是想 他回不了家了...
Well, I just thought that he wouldn't be home...
可能我在教堂能找到他
maybe I'd find him at the church.
你是来杀他的吗
So, you came to blow him away?
不是 长官 他想杀我  我没选择
No sir, he drew on me, tried to kill me. I had no choice.
没选择 牧师告诉我 你让他走的 说他很冷静
No choice? The priest told me you let him go. Said he was calm.
我们永远不会知道 是吗
We'll never know, will we?
就像纽约的DeMarco
It's just like DeMarco in New York.
你一个人出来 而疑犯死了
You come out alone...the suspect is dead.
长官 我们确认了他的身份
Captain, we had a positive lD on...
闭嘴
Shut the fuck up!
我不想个人主义的警察 在我手下办事
I don't want freelance cops working for me!
我要你...
I want you...and you...
明早找国际刑警
lnternal Affairs, tomorrow morning.
别迟到
Don't be late.
别急 我们在找poly
Not so fast. We're sendin' for the poly.
你告诉他什么
So, what'd you tell him?
所有 指纹 过去
Everything. The prints, the bullshit past, the whole nine.
你逼我这么做的 杰克
You didn't leave me any choice, Jack.
嘿 朋友就是这样的吗
Hey, that's what friends are for, right?
我会开始 问你几个问题...
I'll start by asking you a few test questions...
头两个问题回答是
just to establish a base line. Please answer yes to both questions.
-你是侦探Cole  -是
-Are you Detective Jack Cole? -Yes.
-你爬过Mt Everest  -是
-Have you ever climbed Mt. Everest? -Yes.
好 我们开始吧
Okay. Let's begin.
你当警察七年了
You've been a police officer for seven years?
是的
Yes.
你知道你的指纹 留在犯罪现场吗
Do you know how your fingerprints came to be at the crime scene?
不知道
No.
你对这调查有隐藏吗
Are you withholding information pertinent to this investigation?
没有
No.
你开枪射了Christopher Maynard
Did you shoot Christopher Maynard?
是的
Yes.
-是自卫  -是的
-Was it in self-defense? -Yes.
你杀了你前妻
Did you kill your ex-wife?
没有
No.
-你杀过人吗  -杀过
-Have you ever killed anyone? -Yes.
你没有因工作需要而杀人吗
Have you ever killed anyone outside of police duty?
我认为这和调查无关
I don't think that's pertinent to this investigation.
回答有或没有
It's a yes or no answer.
是吗
Is it?
这是我的回答
There's my answer.
别隐瞒什么 杰克
Don't do yourself any favors, Jack.
我没见过这样的东西  都是真的
I've never seen anything like this. Everything reads true.
有可能在这仪器下说谎吗
Can someone learn to beat this thing?
有可能的 不过你得 完全控制你得感情
It's possible, but you'd have to have total control over your emotions.
我不认为有人能
I don't know anybody who could pull that off.
你想我做什么 杰克
What do you want me to do, Jack?
指纹的事已经够坏了
The prints' thing is bad enough, but jerkin' the poly off...
让我们休息会  为了你的fans
just leaves us with our dicks in the air for all your fans.
你得告诉我你在说哪个fans  我有很多个
You gotta tell me which fans you're talkin' about. I have so many.
我在说Frank Deverell
I'm talkin' about Frank Deverell.
他在和人们说你的事
He's talkin' to people about you.
对谁说
Like who?
对DA 说
Like the DA.
你不应该和他孩子在现场
You never should've been on the scene with his kid.
关于你怎么把他推出窗户
About how you put him through a window.
我有点想知道 这个Frank Deverell是不是
I wonder if that's the same Frank Deverell...
那个来感谢我
that came and thanked me...
没把子弹射入他儿子脑袋 的那个
for not shooting his son in the goddamn head.
事情总是在变化的
Yeah, things change.
联邦调查局在调查你 杰克
Internal Affairs is lookin' at you, Jack...
就是他们也在调查我
which means they're lookin' at me, too.
我得暂时撤消你职位 直到我们从这麻烦里脱身
I'm gonna suspend you until we can sort this shit out.
我以为你知道 我是被陷害的
You know, I somehow think that you know I'm gettin' screwed.
好 那就告诉担心的Beads
Yeah, well, tell it to the worry beads.
没人跟你冒险 杰克
No one's takin' any chances with you, Jack.
你是谋杀你前妻和她丈夫的 嫌疑犯
You're officially a suspect in the murder of your ex-wife and her husband.
给我你的身份证 你的徽章 让我们知道你在哪...
Give me your lD, your badge and make sure we know where you are...
因为联邦调查局在查你
'cause lA is comin' for you.
你要哪个
Which one of these did you just piss in?
混蛋
Son of a bitch.
长官 你要见我
Capt., you wanted to see me?
Christopher Maynard和他 的教堂组织在纽约有两星期
Christopher Maynard was with his church group in New York for two weeks.
有消息就告诉我
Keep me posted.
把每分钟都算上 他都没办法干最后两件凶杀
Accounted for every minute. There's no way he could've done the last two.
Cole
Cole?
你告诉我  他因为监护权问题和他前妻吵过
You tell me. He was havin' a custody battle with his ex-wife.
她不想他 和孩子们在一起太多时间
She didn't want him spendin' too much time with the kids.
听着 当他在纽约的时候...
Listen. When he was in New York...
DeMarco凶杀案就在 他调到凶杀部两月后发生
the DeMarco killings started two months after he got assigned to Homicide.
他八个月前来这里
He moved here eight months ago.
准确的说他来之后 两个月那家庭杀手案发生了
Exactly two months after that The Family Man killings start.
也许我们要听听他有什么解释
Maybe we should see what he has to say.
你想对我好一些了 吉姆
What, are you goin' soft on me, Jim?
人是奇怪的 你自己说的
Guy's a weirdo, you said so yourself.
让联邦调查局来处理吧 他们把两件事作为一个案子处理
Just let Internal Affairs handle it. They're puttin' a case together right now.
离他远点
Stay away from him. He's bad news.
有些地方出错了
I take it something is amiss.
他在哪干什么
What was he doing there?
看起来他 不象在找些特别的东西吗
Didn't look like he was after anything specific.
别担心
Nothing to worry about.
没证据把你和Roslov女人联系在一起
Got halfway through the place. Nothing there to connect you to the Roslov woman.
我希望如此
I hope not, for your sake.
你应该几天前就 调查过那房子
You should've gone through that house days ago.
我不想做扫除
I'm not supposed to be doing cleanup.
她在哪 你见过她吗
Where is she? Have you seen her?
不 我找不到她 她离开酒店了
No, I can't find her. She checked out of the hotel.
不过这便条在你刚离开后来的
But this note camejust after you left.
我不能和你去...
"I cannot go with you...
或者再次见到你
"...or ever see you again.
-我爱你 亲爱的  -这是最后一个电话 Richard先生
-"I love you...my darling". -That's the last call, Mr. Richard.
上帝祝福你
"God bless you".
-发生什么事了  -到底怎么了
-What's happenin'? -What's up?
-你到底在这干什么  -我们要谈一下
-What the hell you doin' here? -Gotta talk.
-那不是眼泪吧  -不是
-Those aren't tears, are they? -No, man.
我打哈欠时就会流眼泪 如此而已
My eyes leak sometimes when I yawn, that's all.
-你眼睛流泪  -是的
-They leak? -Yeah.
-你眼睛流泪  -你想怎么样
-They leak. -What do you want?
-让我  -等等 我没事
-Let me just... -Wait...I'm fine.
你想怎样
What do you want?
我得和你谈话  好啊
-I gotta talk to you. -All right, come on.
如果有个连环杀手逍遥法外...
What if there's a serial killer out there...
他杀了很多家庭 我们叫他家庭杀手
he's killin' families, we nickname him "The Family Man".
不过还有别人...
But there's somebody else out there...
做更阴险的事
who has somethin' more sinister goin' on.
他想把他对头杀掉
He has to terminate some targets.
他杀了他的对头的全家...
So, he kills his targets and their entire families to make himself...
让人看起来象家庭杀手的手法
look like The Family Man.
当我们在找那个连环杀手时
While we're lookin' for a serial killer.
实际上有两个人 而其中一个才是专业
When, in fact, there's two of 'em and one of 'em is a pro.
-你怎么知道他是专业  -专业才做得出这样的杰作
-How do you know it's a pro? -'Cause I know the work of a pro.
我在Sonya Roslov的房间里找到这个
I found this in Sonya Roslov's house.
这是去莫斯科的往返机票
It's a round trip to Moscow...
Deverell 企业支付的
bought and paid for by Deverell Industries.
你认为Deverell和这事 有关系
You think Frank Deverell had somethin' to do with this?
是的
I do, sir.
她是个翻译
Sonya Roslov, she was a translator.
如果Deverell在俄罗斯有生意的话
If Deverell did any business in Russia...
他请那样的人也不奇怪
it makes sense he'd hire someone like that.
如果她是个走私犯呢  走私什么
-What if she was a mule? -Smuggling what?
化学武器什么的
Chemical weapons of some kind.
墙倒了...
Now that the Wall fell...
到处是涌进来的东西
there's a ton of that stuff floatin' around.
那能解释她的癌症
That would explain the cancer in her body.
如果你发现谁在黑市 控制这玩意...
If you look at who controls that stuff on the black market...
是俄罗斯黑帮
it's the Russian Mafia.
和袭击我们的一样  是的
-As in the guys who jumped us. -You got it.
这样 那什么把Dunleavys和Deverell 联系起来呢
So, what connects the Dunleavys to Deverell?
我还不知道 不过我知道我们 会找出来的
I don't know yet, but I know we could find out.
你知道 他们会收了我的徽章  如果他们知道我和你一起调查
You know, they will take my badge if they find out I'm workin' with you.
不过我直觉告诉我你可能是对的
But, my gut tells me you might be right.
-我一直相信我的直觉  -好的
-I always go with my gut. -Okay.
我对你不了解 但我会 看完剩下的电影
I don't know about you, but I'm gonna go see the rest of this movie.
是个好电影吗
Is it a good movie?
你没看过Casablanca
You've never seen Casablanca?
你在问我有没看过Casablanca
You're asking me if I've ever seen Casablanca?
你看过
Have you?
你在开玩笑吧 没看过
You gotta be kidding. Me? Never seen Casablanca?
你看过吗
Have you ever seen Casablanca?
没看过
No.
不会吧
Come on.
当然 Donald没失去任何东西 除了他的自尊
And of course, Donald survived with everything but his pride intact.
我没想到Cole
I never expected Cole to get this close.
我想你最好 看牢点你的前雇员
I thought you kept better track of your ex-employees.
没有迹象他和 这有关
No way to anticipate he'd become this involved.
他是谁 很明显不仅仅是个警察
Who is he? Obviously not just a cop.
他是个优秀的战士  西点之类
He was a brilliant soldier. West Point, that kind of thing.
我在越南找到他 把他编入特别行动组
I found him in Vietnam. Recruited him for a special projects unit.
我们对那程序的称呼
The Program, we called it.
他为我们处理了很多奇怪的事
He handled a lot of odd jobs for us.
-例如  -现在 Deverell先生...
-Such as? -Now, Mr. Deverell...
别问你并不想 知道的事
don't ask about things you don't really want to know.
对于他追捕的那些人...
Suffice to say, to the people he hunted for us...
他被称为"魔鬼尖兵"
he was known as "The Glimmer Man".
除了丛林什么都没有...
There'd be nothing but jungle...
而后一闪...
then a glimmer...
然后你就死了
then you'd be dead.
为什么他不和你一起了
Why isn't he still with you?
他84年离开了特别行动组 对我们来说很正常
He was booted out of the program in '84. Went native on us.
他有了他自己的安排
Made up his own assignments.
消失了几个月
Disappeared...for months.
在泰国出现
Ended up in Thailand...
在一些庙里唱着圣歌
chanting in some temple or other.
他们说他被一个圣人救了
They say he was saved by a holy man.
这家伙这么多故事  我都不知哪个事真的
So many stories about this fella, I don't know which ones are true anymore.
我们要对他怎样呢  清除他
-What do we do about him? -Broom him.
是除去知道 事情的人的时候了
Time to lose everybody who knows anythin'.
我说的是所有人
And I mean everybody.
Johny没威胁啊
Johnny's no threat.
我不这么认为 他已经 和这事脱不开了
I beg to differ. He's already spilled to the shrink.
那可怜的孩子知道太多了  就这么简单
The poor boy knows too much. Simple as that.
Johnny会听我的话的
Johnny'll do what I say.
让我这样说
Let me put this another way.
这案子有四条线索
I have four loose links in this operation:
两个警察 你和这孩子
Two cops, you, and the boy.
你们中的三个得死
Three of you have to go.
你能选是哪三个
You can choose which three.
你得自己去决定
You'll have to do it yourself.
Frank 我负责Johnny
Frank, I'll take care of Johnny.
我们得照料Cole和Campbell
Who's gonna take care of Cole and Campbell?
我会派Donald处理其他人
I'll put Donald on the others right away.
这就对了
That's the spirit.
来啊 水很好
Now, come on in. The water's fine.
混蛋
Shit!
把孩子带到楼上去
Take the kids upstairs.
-John Cole  -是的
-John Cole? -Yes.
我们是联邦调查局的Miller 和 Russo
Miller and Russo from Internal Affairs.
我们有你的拘捕证
We have a warrant for your arrest.
你需要收拾些东西吗
Do you want to take a minute to gather a few things?
不用 我准备好走了
No, that's perfectly all right. I'm ready to go.
我记忆中洛杉矶最冷的冬天
Coldest winter I can remember in LA.
也是最湿的
Wettest, too.
他们也对付你
They got you, too.
不 在暴乱后我买下了所有的毒品
No, I bought all this shit after the riots.
表示我们是一起的 我们在同一条船上
It means we're close, man, we're close.
我看起来像
Do I look like I give a shit?
因为他们要抓到我们两
You better give a shit, 'cause they ain't gonna stop till they get us both.
这是鹿角
Does this say, "deer antler"?
给我
Give me that.
-这是个免费的例子  -整个案子就在这
-It was a free sample. -There's a whole case over here.
离开我
Just stay out of my shit.
我能告诉你 我现在到底有多激动吗
Can I just take this moment to tell you how moved I am deeply?
好的
Yeah, well, that makes one of us.
我在你前妻的电话记录里发现了些东西
I found somethin' on your ex-wife's phone records.
有人在她被杀那晚给她打了电话
Someone called the house the night she was killed.
他们打了六次 每次 只谈了15秒
They called six times, only talked about 10 or 15 seconds each time.
你有号码吗
You got a number or somethin'?
我能拿那些CD吗  看起来我用得着它们
Could I take those CDs? They look like I could still use them.
拿啊
Got it. Come on.
我能问你些事吗  你真得住在这鬼地方
Could I ask you somethin'? Did you actually live in this shitbox?
嘿 你能不能合作些
Man, will you come on?
现在 如果真是我们的人怎么办
Now, what if this is really our guy?
-我们会和他理论  -好
-We'll reason with him. -Right.
-什么  -警察
-What? -Police!
我是侦探Cole 这是侦探Campbell...
I'm Detective Cole, this is Detective Campbell...
我们是洛杉矶警察局的
with the Los Angeles Police Department.
我们想问你些关于 一些电话的问题...
We'd like to ask you some questions about some calls...
你可能得联系Dr Dunleavy
you may have made to a Dr. Dunleavy.
你看起来像刚打完仗
You look like you just came from a riot.
多谢
Thanks.
他看起来像刚打完仗
He looks like he just came from a riot.
是的 这个号码的帐单给我  不过这是我女儿的电话
Yeah, this number's billed to me, but it's my daughter's phone.
我认识你吧
I know you, don't I?
是的 你认识我 你把我 男朋友推下一扇窗户
Yeah, you know me. You put my boyfriend through a window.
高中的窗户 我想起来了
High school, window. I remember now.
你是Johnny Deverell的女朋友 是吧
You're Johnny Deverell's girlfriend, aren't you?
那如何
So?
我想知道你认识Dr  Dunleavy多久了
So, I was just wondering, how long have you known Dr. Dunleavy?
我不认识什么Dunleavy
I don't know any Dunleavy.
你在他被杀的那晚给他打过电话
You called him the night he was killed.
哦 那不是我 我不需要一个精神病医生
Yeah. Well, it wasn't me. I don't need a shrink.
我们没说过他是精神病医生
We never said he was a shrink.
好的 我认识他但我没打电话给他
Okay, I knew him but I didn't call him.
我想知道谁打的
I wonder who did?
Johnny 打的
Johnny did.
他们让他去看 一个精神病医生
When he got busted with the coke, they made him see a shrink.
这个精神病医生是Dunleavy 对吗
The shrink was Dunleavy, right?
Millie
Millie.
让我告诉你些事情 甜心 游戏结束了
Let me tell you something, sweetheart, the games are over.
我要你现在告诉我...
I want you to tell me right now...
为什么Johnny要从这房间 打电话
why Johnny was making phone calls from this room.
他不敢从家里打
He was afraid to call from home.
为什么
Why?
他的继父 Johnny知道 他继父在干些不好的事情
His stepfather. Johnny knew some bad things he was doing.
你知道我们到哪能找到 那孩子吗
Would you happen to know where we could find this boy?
他继父把他带走了
His stepfather put him away at Our Lady Of Angels.
你认为Deverell会 杀他自己的儿子吗
You don't think Deverell would kill his own stepson, do you?
蠢问题 让我们离开这里
Right. Dumb question. Let's get out of here.
-你好吗 Johnny  -是的 没这么好过
-You all right, Johnny? -Yeah, never been better.
我们要问你些 关于你继父的问题
Yeah, we need to ask some questions about your stepdad.
他是个混蛋
He's a prick.
是的 除了那个
Yeah, besides that.
你父亲杀了Dunleavy
Did your dad kill Dunleavy?
是的 我想打电话告诉他 我想提醒他 我对天发誓
Yeah, I tried to call him, I tried to warn him, I swear to God.
我们知道 没事的
We know, we know. It's all right.
所有人都冷静下来 警察
All right, everybody just relax. Police.
他为什么这样做
Why'd he do it?
好的 他让Donald杀了他的翻译...
Okay, he had Donald kill his translator...
因为她知道我父亲 从俄罗斯走私些不好的东西
because she knew that my father was smugglin' in some bad shit from Russia.
我发现了它
And I found out about it.
所以他发怒了 认为我告诉了Dr Dunleavy
So, he got all freaked out, and thought I told Dr. Dunleavy.
所以他让Donald杀了他和他妻子
So he had Donald kill him and his wife...
然后让它看起来想连环杀手干的
and made it look like the serial killer did it.
谁在帮他
Who was helpin' him?
一些人
Some little guy.
南方口音...
Southern accent....
-Smith  -是的 政府的那家伙
-Smith. -Yeah, the government guy.
谁是Smith
Who's Smith?
你会知道的
You're about to find out.
而且留意他
Sister, take this boy and keep an eye on him.
别让他出什么事 别让他一个人
Don't let anything happen to him. Don't leave him alone.
当然 我会照顾你的 Johnny
Yes, of course. I'll take care of you, Johnny. Come.
再见 Joe
See you later, Joe.
你在做什么
How you doin'?
杰克 多好的惊喜
Jack, what a pleasant surprise...
你知道吗 在一些州
You know, in most states in this country...
绑架仍然不允许 我们不能再做了
kidnapping is still a no-no. Hell, we don't even do it anymore.
帮我个忙 告诉我个
Do me a favor. Spare me the drama and...
故事 Deverell走私些什么
tell me a story. What's Deverell smuggling?
我不知道你在说什么
I have no idea what you're talking about.
真的
Really?
上帝 杰克 你在干什么
Goddamn, Jack! What are you doin', man?
杀了四个人去隐瞒些东西 而我想找出来到底是什么
Deverell's killed four people to hide something, and I want to find out what.
你是个神经病人
You're a fuckin' psycho.
我不知道他在说些什么
I don't know what the hell he's talkin' about.
好的 你是个警察
Well, you're a cop!
你准备开始帮忙了吗
Aren't you gonna help?
好的
Okay.
不过我真的不太懂射击
But I'm a really bad shot.
-离开这里  -我只想帮忙
-Stay out of it. -I'm just tryin' to help.
如果你喜欢就杀了我 混蛋
Kill me if you like, you son of a bitch.
我还是不明白 你在说什么
I still have no idea what you're talkin' about.
杰克 我知道我们以前 不好...
Jack, I know we've had some harsh words in the past....
我告诉你我不知道 好的...
-I tell you I do not know... -Okay....
我要那手 杰克 我要那手
I need that hand. Jack, I need that hand.
你知道我会的
You know I will. Right about....
好的 游戏结束
All right! Time! Game over!
我真想你 杰克
God I miss you, Jack.
这么多年轻人 都不肯坚持久些
So many young men today just won't go that extra mile.
我也想你 Smith 那是什么
I miss you too, Smith. Now, what is it?
Deverell 在走私...
Deverell is smugglin'...
化学武器
chemical weapons in from Russia.
我帮他签合同 俄罗斯黑帮介绍的生意
I made the contacts for him. The deal's being brokered by the Russian Mafia.
你们不介意 帮我叫辆救护车吧
Would one of you gentlemen mind callin' me an ambulance?
他到底用那些东西干什么呢
So, what's he doin' with this stuff?
明天会有交易 在乡下的酒店里
Deal's bein' done tomorrow. Some welfare hotel downtown.
他把那些卖给 塞尔维亚自由战士
He's sellin' it to a bunch of Serbian freedom fighters.
你的意思是恐怖主义者
You mean terrorists.
语法上来说 你说番茄...
Semantics. You say tomato...
不 混蛋 我没说番茄  我是说恐怖主义者
No, motherfucker, I didn't say, "tomato". I said, "terrorists".
你为政府工作
You work for the government.
为什么你们所有人都 帮Deverell
Why would you, of all people, help Deverell?
为了钱 还能为什么
To get rich, son. To get rich, why else?
你有钱了
You got that?
是的
Yeah, I got that.
好的 你是个成熟的特工
Well, aren't you the grown-up spy?
你想要什么
What do you want?
我想你和你的朋友别缠着我 忘了我
I want you and your friends to leave me alone. Forget that I exist.
我已经这么做了
I already have.
别逼我回来杀了你
Don't make me come back and kill you.
-我不会的  -好的
-I won't. -Good.
先生们 我们别忘了...
Gentlemen, we must not forget the little matter...
救护车 我只射伤了你一条腿
of the ambulance. -I only shot you in one foot.
你拐着去医院
Hobble to a hospital.
好的 伙计 最恶劣的冬天 已经过去了
Well, safe to assume, folks, that the rainiest winter in memory is over.
阳光灿烂的明天 就要来了
Sunny and dry weather for tomorrow and for the entire five-day period.
我们能期望的是...
Everything we could hope for in this part of the country....
Deverell从俄罗斯走私化学武器
Deverell is smugglin' chemical weapons in from Russia.
交易是由俄罗斯黑帮 联系的
The deal's bein' brokered by the Russian Mafia.
-你是谁  -这样如何 杂种
-Who is this? -So, how's that, asshole?
我知道你是所有人的朋友 从邮递员到总统...
I know you're friends with everyone from the postman to the President...
不过没人会再理你
but no one will touch you with a ten-foot pole...
当这个被捅出来时 明白吗
when this shit gets out. Understand?
侦探 Cole
Detective Cole.
你很坚持 我会给你那个的
You are persistent, I'll give you that.
看起来我有你要的东西 而你有我要的东西
Looks like I got somethin' you want, you got somethin' I want.
-那是什么
-What might that be? -Donald.
Donald是你的杀手 是吗
Donald's your triggerman, isn't he?
我在听
I'm listening.
我要他 不是你
I want him, not you.
把他和他作案武器交给我
Deliver him to me with a nice bow and the murder weapon.
我会去那拿的
I'll take it from there.
你把磁带拿来  我没事 你们也没事
You take the tape...my name gets clean...your name stays clean.
所有人都满意 怎么样
Everybody's happy, how's that?
好的
Done.
你为什么不明天来见我呢
Why don't you meet me tomorrow?
我在Ovinton Arms有点事
I'm doing a little business at a place called the Ovington Arms, downtown.
公寓 D-14  10点好吗
Apartment D-14. Would 10:00 be good for you?
为什么要这么复杂
Why does this gotta be so complicated?
不复杂  只是场游戏
This isn't complicated. It's nothing but a game.
让我想起一个老波斯战略家...
Reminds me of an old Persian tactician...
教导他年轻部队战术
trying to teach his young troops strategy.
后来变得象下棋一样
That, later on, came to be known as chess.
我们要把他们烦死吗
So, we're gonna bore 'em to death now?
年轻的战士开始 喜欢战斗了
Young warriors used to like to fight head-on.
老战士喜欢等...
Old warriors like to wait...
让对手充分暴露 从而陷入绝境
let their opponents expose the board, work themselves into a corner....
该走了 孙武 战争艺术
Time to go. Sun Tzu, The Art of War.
孙武 更奇怪了
Sun Tzu. Just keeps gettin' stranger.
onald是你的杀手 是吗
Donald's your triggerman, isn't he?
我在听
I'm listening.
我要他 不是你
I want him, not you.
把他和他的作案武器交给我
Deliver him to me with a nice bow and the murder weapon.
我会在那拿的
I'll take it from there.
拿磁带来 我没事
Take the tape...my name gets clean...
你也没事  所有人都满意 怎么样
your name stays clean. Everybody's happy, how's that?
成交
Done.
你这混蛋刚被出卖
Guess your ass just got sold down the river, shithead.
不会太长时间的
This won't take long. Just a quick pick up.
我肯定它时间不长
I'm sure it won't.
真破 不过挺奇特
Shabby, but chic.
要不是我们早了...
Either we're a little early...
就时我们的主人来晚了
or our hosts are a little late.
到底怎么回事 Donald
What the hell is going on, Donald?
你告诉我
You tell me.
你认为你能把我交给Cole
You think you're gonna hand me over to Cole. Bad move, fruitcake.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
你离不开这里了
You'll never get out of here.
不 我的表演现在开始
No, this is my show from now on.
肯定事莎士比亚风格
Positively Shakespearean.
是
"To be...
要不就不是
"...or not to be!"
该走了
Time to go.
等等 我们不知道 这有多少人
Wait. We don't know how many guys are in there.
你想我干什么  等他们互相残杀吗
What do you want me to do? Wait till they all kill each other?
如果老战士有耐心...
If the old warriors are patient and...
而年轻战士相互惨杀
all the young warriors, they kill each other and...
这就是我们为什么老的原因
that's how we get to be old.
我喜欢这个计划 你听好
I like that plan too. You listened well.
那是我在酒吧你告诉你的
That's what I told you in the bar.
我不知道为什么我不听自己的话 我真笨
I don't know why I don't listen to myself. I'm stupid.
我们等吧
Let's just wait.
把枪放下 警察
Drop the guns! Police!
放下你的枪
Put your guns down!
放下枪
Drop that fuckin' gun!
立刻放下枪
Drop the gun now!
把枪放下
Drop the gun, boy.
别动
Freeze!
放下
Just drop it!
你也是
You, too!
你住哪
Where do you live?
-拐过那个拐角  -好的 你这混蛋快拐过拐角
-Around the corner. -Well, get your ass around the corner!
把Whoopi Goldberg带上
And take little Whoopi Goldberg with you.
上帝
Jesus Christ.
在芝麻街最后摊牌
Showdown on Sesame Street.
大Bird会带你们从另一道门突出去
Big Bird will pop out of one of these doors next.
Hi
Hi!
离开这里
Out here!
快点 我不能坚持太久
Hurry, man! I can't hold on much longer!
噢 上帝 别往下看
Oh, God, don't look down. Don't look down.
噢 别往上看
Oh, don't look up.
好的 坚持一下
All right, hang on.
是个好主意
Yeah. That's a good idea, man.
我不应该想到这个主意
I wouldn't have thought of that.
好的 你准备好了吗  准备什么
-All right, are you ready? -Ready for what?
这个
For this.
有个窗户 杰克
There's a window, Jack! There's a window!
这是你的枪 还是你太兴奋了
Is that your gun or are you gettin' excited, man?
走开
Get off me. Get off.
警方例行公事 我们已经到这儿了
Police business. We're right on out of here.
-你能到那大厅里去吗  -好的 我会没事的
-Can you make it down to the lobby? -Yeah, I'll be all right.
电梯坏了
The elevator was broken.
以前有人告诉过你你是个混蛋吗
Has anybody ever told you you're a real pain in the ass?
一直
All the time.
你不会再听到了
You're not gonna have to hear it anymore.
我会像对你前妻一样 对付你
I'm gonna take care of you like I took care of your ex-wife.
我们在这
Here we are.
当你早上醒来 照镜子的时候...
When you wake up in the morning and look in the mirror...
我想你会高兴的...
l think you're probably happy...
而那使我烦恼
pleased at what you see. And that disturbs me.
作为我的责任 我得这么做...
So, I'm gonna take it on as my responsibility...
确保你不会 再照镜子
to make sure that you never get to look in the mirror again.
我醒来会很高兴 因为 你死了
I woke up happy, I'm going to bed happy 'cause you're gonna be dead.
射准点
Take your best shot.
不是 我是说 射准
No, I said, "Best shot".
无聊
Boring.
你最好只能如此吗
Is that the best you got, boy?
如果你只能如此 那我就不得不杀你了
If that's the best you got, I'm just gonna have to kill you.
你就这么两下吗
Is that all you got?
看来你不能 醒来时高兴了
You don't look like you're gonna be wakin' up happy now.
嘿 长官
Hey, Capt.
你看起来有些粗暴 Campbell
You're looking a little rough there, Campbell.
他们说我得搞定它
Yeah, well, they say I'm gonna make it.
我对你抱歉 杰克
Guess I owe you an apology, Jack.
上帝 那不好吗
God, wouldn't that be nice?
你不会得到得
Well, you're not gonna get it.
不过我欠你的啊
But I do owe it to you.
帮我个忙 告诉我妻子我活着 而且很好
Do me a favor, tell my wife I'm alive and well.
你清楚
You got it.
感觉好点了 孩子
Feel better, kid.
嗯
Yeah.
杰克 如果我们几天没说话会如何
Say, Jack. How about we not talk for a couple of days?
我说了什么
Somethin' I said?
从你做我的搭档开始
It's just that ever since you started bein' my partner...
我被打 被枪击
I've been beat up, blown up...
被从窗户踢出去
shot, kicked out a window...
我所有的东西都被烧了
all my worldly possessions burnt to a crisp.
准确的说 我无家可归
Basically, I'm homeless.
从我遇到你后就没好事发生过
Not one good thing has happened since I met you.
你得试试鹿阳粉
You got to try powdered deer penis.
那会有用的
That should count for something.
别打我电话 别给我留言
Don't call me, Jack. Don't leave me a message.
也别给我传真 如果 我在我窗户看到一只鸟腿上绑着纸条...
Don't fax me. If I see a bird on my window with a message on its foot...
我会把它扔出去
I'm throwin' him back out.
别送花来
Don't send flowers.
忘了你认识我 杰克
Forget you know me, Jack!